

# Ana García del Molino

I am in my final year of PhD. at I2R and NTU, Singapore, currently working on Visual Memory and Summarization from First Person View content. My research interests are in the areas of computer vision, multimedia and personalization.



Spain, May 17th 1990



garciadelmolino.github.io □ ana002@ntu.edu.sg



(+65) 86021449



S ana.garcia.del.molino

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



**INSTITUTE FOR INFOCOMM RESEARCH, A\*STAR**, Research Assistant Aug 2014 - Today Ph.D. student position at the REVIVE project. My research focuses on the integration of cognitive models into computer vision systems, towards efficient visual memory organization and retrieval.



**GIFS.COM**, Research Consultant

Jun 2017 - Sept 2017

The project included improving their automatic GIF generation engine by personalizing the experience. The new model generates different GIFs depending on the user's previous searches.



NANYANG TECHONOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY, Teaching Assistant

Fall 2016

Teacher at the Algorithms CE2001 module lab (Computer Science Yr. 2).



**PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPERS**, Systems Auditor

Nov 2013 - Aug 2014

Systems & Process Assurance Auditor for annual audits in several multinational companies.

**NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF INFORMATICS, TOKYO**, Research Intern Mar 2013 - Sep 2013 Intern at Shin'ichi Satoh's group. Participation in TRECVID Instance Search 2013 while researching for my Master Thesis.



**UPC IMAGE AND VIDEO PROCESSING GROUP**, Research Intern Apr 2012 - Mar 2013 Research in several projects for Mediapro, including a basketball tracking system.

## **EDUCATION**



#### PHD. IN COGNITIVE SYSTEMS AND VISUAL COMPUTING

Jan 2015 - Today

School of Computer Science and Engineering, NTU, Singapore

GPA 4.63/5. Coursework requirements fulfilled: Cognitive Neuroscience & Embodied Intelligence; Human Computer Interaction; Digital Image Processing; Multimedia Information Management.



#### BSC. AND MSC. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

Sep 2008 - Sep 2013

TelecomBCN (ETSETB, UPC Barcelona Tech), Spain

Bachelor and Master Degree with specialty in Communications.

9.5/10 qualification for my Thesis, average grade of 7.33/10, order 33/144 and efficiency of 0.94.

## **HONORS & AWARDS**



SINGA SCHOLARSHIP

Jan 2015

Singaporean scholarship for the PhD. joint program between A\*STAR and NTU. Obra Social

OBRA SOCIAL "LA CAIXA" Apr 2015 Scholarship to cover additional conference and travel expenses during my PhD.

## **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

- **A. G. del Molino**, JH Lim, AH Tan, "Predicting Visual Context for Unsupervised Event Segmentation in Continuous Photo-streams," in *Proceedings of ACM Multimedia conference*. ACM, Oct 2018
- **A. G. del Molino**, M. Gygli, "PHD-GIFs: Personalized Highlight Detection for Automatic GIF Creation," in *Proceedings of ACM Multimedia conference*. ACM, Oct 2018
- **A. G. del Molino**, X. Boix, JH Lim, AH Tan, "Active Video Summarization: Customized Summaries via On-line Interaction with the User," in *AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence*, Feb 2017.
- **A. G. del Molino**, C. Tan, J. H. Lim and A. H. Tan, "Summarization of Egocentric Videos: A Comprehensive Survey," in *IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine Systems*, 47 (1), 65-76, Jan 2017.

#### OTHER PUBLICATIONS

- A. G. del Molino, B. Mandal, J. Lin, J. H. Lim, V. Subbaraju, V. Chandrasekhar, "VC-I2R@ Image-CLEF2017: ensemble of deep learned features for lifelog video summarization," in *CLEF working notes*, pp. 11–14. Sep 2017.
- **A. G. del Molino**, Q. Xu, and J. H. Lim, "Describing Lifelogs with Convolutional Neural Networks: A Comparative Study," in *Proceedings of the first Workshop on Lifelogging Tools and Applications*, pp. 39-44. ACM, 2016.
- **A. G. del Molino**, B. Mandal, L. Li, and J. H. Lim, "Organizing and Retrieving Episodic Memories from First Person View," in *International Conference on Multimedia & Expo Workshops (ICMEW)*, pp. 1-6. IEEE, 2015.

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Native Speaker

Native Speaker

TOEFL iBT 103/120

European B2.2

Basic European A1

Matlab, Python, C++, OpenCV, TensorFlow, Keras, HTML, CSS, etc Linux user. Proficient in both Office tools and 上下X Basic knowledge in video and audio editors.

A few pleasures: sailing, traveling, board games, cooking, painting, reading, playing the flute and the piano, cinema, opera...

Make the most of your hobbies! I was a sailing instructor in Barcelona the summers of '08 to '12.

Causes that matter. I am part of the leadership of the Artificial Intelligence Singapore LeanIn Circle. I also collaborate in activities organized by GirlsInTech.

Commitment to the community. During my undergrad, I was part of several student associations: Vice-President of the IEEE Barcelona Student Branch in 2011-2013; Active member of the Student's Delegation; intern at the International Student Office; Member of the student group at ETSETB's Evaluation Committee and Board.

## **REFEREES**



LIM JOO-HWEE I2R, A\*STAR My PhD. research supervisor joohwee@i2r.a-star.edu.sg



**XAVI GIRO-I-NIETO** ETSETB, UPC My MSc. supervisor and councelor xavier.giro@upc.edu



**TAN AH-HWEE** SCSE, NTU My PhD. accademic supervisor ASAHTan@ntu.edu.sg



FERRAN MARQUES ETSETB, UPC
My BSc. and MSc. mentor
ferran.marques@upc.edu